get lowest number like this we will wait
and that should give us
the lowest number say function and look
at that
boy as you can see done that is crazy
[Applause]
nicolas and today we're going to talk
about github
co-pilot the ai tool from github that
may or may not replace
developers github co-pilot is an ai
powered suggestion tool for developers
what that means for you and me
is that now instead of writing the code
of a whole function what we do instead
is we write a comment of what the
function should do
and co-pilot is going to generate the
whole code for us
i've got an invite to test copilot and
since i've tried it i felt many
different emotions first i was shocked
about how good it is then i was scared
because it might really replace
developers and then i got angry
because of what they did with all the
code that we gave them and now i'm happy
and i feel hopeful about the future so i
want to share all this with you
before we jump in the demo let me first
give you some background information
copilot is powered by an algorithm
called open ai codex
codex is a descendant of open ai gpd3
gb3 is a very famous algorithm that we
made a video about
last year but what it basically does is
that it creates text just as good as
humans
it was fed all the text on the internet
literally as much text as possible
comments reviews blog posts news it was
fed all that
and it learned how to write text just
like humans do it's almost
indiscernible when a human writes and
when deputies writes
again we made a video about it so check
it out if you want to learn more now
codex which is this new algorithm was
also trained in a lot of
data but the data it was trained on
wasn't just text and comments and
whatever
the data was all the public code
available
on github that's right all the code that
you and me
have been pushing to github so happily
because it's for free
has been used to train an ai tool that
maybe is going to replace us and write
better code than we do
open ai was created by elon musk and
other people as a non-profit
organization to ensure that artificial
general intelligence
benefits humanity but now they changed
from non-profit
to cap profit and they received one
billion dollars
from microsoft to exclusively license
their ai technology so maybe it's not
open ai anymore it's more like closed ai
or microsoft ai it's worth remembering
that microsoft owns
github they also have a cloud provider
which is called
azure and they are the ones that make
visual studio code so as you can see
everything goes full circle i made a
video last year talking about microsoft
plans for developer market domination
but i would have never imagined they're
going to do something like this so
now that we have the context let's
actually look at the demo and see how
good and scary
co-pilot is to use copilot we have two
options one option would be to write the
name of the function
in a very descriptive way so we can say
function
get lowest number like this
we will wait and that should give us the
lowest number that
is crazy or we can write a comment
find lowest number
using binary search say function
and look at that find tesla
stock price today function will
wait boy as you can see now he's working
with api that is insane
get the tweets of a user
function will wait done
that is crazy get today's
weather function
booyah open weather api that is crazy
we can also give some context like for
example express
app running on port 3000 and we say
receive
a file from a user and
save it to disk we do app that
and we wait here it is
that was crazy that is crazy now of
course it works in other
programming languages like go for
example we can say find
the youngest user we say func will wait
i can also say create a new user
and here i will just create a function
and as you can see i can
open also some suggestions of some
solutions that might happen
this solution is doing something
different this solution is doing
something different
this solution maybe is doing what i want
so i will accept this solution
so as you can see you can also choose
from a list of possible solutions that
is amazing
also we can work with css and we can say
make a big
red circle and we can start
to see suggestions and accepting those
suggestions
okay and we are good to go as you can
see it added some extra things that i
didn't want
but still good enough as you can see
it's pretty impressive it's
mind-blowing it's too mind-blowing this
is when i got scared because this thing
is
not good it's actually too good even the
ceo of
open ai the company that has all this
technology made a very scary
prediction and i quote he said ai will
cause the price of work that can happen
in front of a computer to decrease much
faster
than the price of work that happens in
the physical world
this means that maybe replacing a
developer or a designer somebody that
works on a computer is easier than
replacing a truck driver or somebody
that's working on a farm
this is when i remember the strategy
that microsoft is very famous for
which is embrace extend and extinguish
microsoft acquired github and made it
for free they also gave us visual studio
code and we all used it
now we used both of these two tools to
create and store the code that they
used to make a tool that might actually
replace
developers and it makes sense that they
do this because developers
are what these companies rely on the
developers are expensive
so maybe they're just going to replace
developers so maybe now companies are
not going to hire developers instead
they will pay microsoft
to give them access to this ai magic
that is going to write code for them
so this is when i got angry but then the
more i used co-pilot the more i tried to
do things with it the more i realized
that it isn't perfect
it makes mistakes and of course you need
a programmer to be able to spot those
mistakes and fix them
because remember this a i think these
algorithms they don't know what
code is they don't know how code works
they just know how code
look like copilot just gives you code
but you have to evaluate if it's good
and if it actually works
you the developer so the more and more i
keep using it i realize that this is not
going to really replace developers
instead maybe it's going to replace or
is a threat to websites like for example
stack overflow the code that copilots
suggest
is not guaranteed to be code that works
it's even on their website
i quote github compiler that doesn't
actually test the code it suggests
so the code may not even compile or run
according to a study made by cambridge
developers spend
50 percent of their time not programming
half of the rest of the time is spent on
debugging
so that means that with copilot we're
going to maybe write code faster and
where we before we're trying to debug
mistakes that we made now we're going to
debug mistakes that the machine made
keep in mind that copilot is trained
on already existing code created by
humans
co-pilot is a reflection of our code
this means that co-pilot was
trained with buggy code and it might and
it will
give you a bug solution also remember
copilot just waits for you
you the developer are the one that has
to decide if you're going to use an
array or an object you
the developer have to choose between
using binary or linear search you have
to know what these things
are so you can tell co-pilot what you
want programming is about solving
problems with creative solutions
copilot will just help you implement
solutions faster but you
the developer are the creative force now
we can spend
less time doing manual work and writing
the same functions that a thousand
of developers already wrote before us
and instead we can focus
on doing cool stuff creating things
which is what we
are doing programming for i'm curious to
see what happens in the future what
happens when we use copilot and we push
that co-pilot generated code into github
and then
copilot learns from itself maybe the
code will
get better it will get worse i don't
know or maybe in the future we're going
to have companies
hiring people to exclusively just clean
code that was created
by ai or maybe we will have companies
that are not going to allow
their employees to use copilot for
security reasons
or maybe somebody is going to put some
co-pilot generated code in some very
important system and there's going to be
a bug who is it to blame the developer
is it microsoft is it the ai i don't
know many questions arise
but overall i think it's a very good
thing for developers
so as you can see there are many
questions that will arise but we'll only
see the answer to them in the future but
for now i feel
happy i feel hopeful i don't feel scared
i don't think it's going to replace
developers it will definitely not
i think when you see it on the landing
page of github it looks like it's the
end
but when you try it you realize nope we
are not even close this is going just to
be something for productivity
we are not even close to replacing
developers anytime soon
something funny is that if i ask copilot
what is the worst programming language
it will say javascript which i think is
interesting thank you so much for
watching please be happy today don't
forget to read ginji come to me that
sound hello
don't be scared we're not gonna replace
anytime soon see you on the next one